Finding Aid for the Papers of Virginia Woolf, 1902-1956
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
Papers of Virginia Woolf
1902-1956
Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941
MS 1
6 boxes, 217 items 2.25 linear ft.
Mortimer Rare Book Room Smith College Northampton, MA
Influential English writer best remembered for her innovative stream-of-consciousness novels. Papers include correspondence, reading notes, drafts of essays and short stories, corrected page proofs of novels and collected essays, printed ephemera, and photographs.
1882 25 January: Born Adeline Virginia Stephen.
1895 5 May: Death of mother, Julia Stephen.
1899 Virginia's brother, Thoby Stephen, attends Cambridge, where he meets members of the future Bloomsbury Group (Lytton Strachey, Leonard Woolf, Clive Bell).
1904 22 February: Death of father, Leslie Stephen. Travels in Italy. Moves to Gordon Square. 14 December: Virginia's first publication, an unsigned review, appears in the Guardian.
1905 Travels in Spain and Portugal.
1906 Travels in Greece. 20 November: Death of brother, Thoby Stephen.
1907 7 February: Marriage of Vanessa Stephen and Clive Bell. April: Moves to 29 Fitzroy Square.
1908 4 February: Nephew Julian Bell is born.
1909 17 February: Lytton Strachey proposes marriage to Virginia, and she accepts. The engagement is soon called off.
1910 19 August: Nephew Claudian [Quentin] Bell is born.
1912 10 August: Marries Leonard Woolf.
1913 Suicide attempt.
1915 March: The Voyage Out (originally entitled Melymbrosia) is published.
1917 Formation of Hogarth Press.
1918 May: Lytton Strachey's Eminent Victorians is published.
1919 July: The Woolfs buy Monk's House. 20 October: Publication of Night and Day.
1921 March: Publication of Monday or Tuesday.
1922 October: Jacob's Room published. December: Meets Vita Sackville-West.
1924 Moves to 52 Tavistock Square.
1925 April: Publication of The Common Reader. May: Publication of Mrs. Dalloway
1927 May: To the Lighthouse is published.
1928 Awarded Femina Vie Heureuse prize. October: Publication of Orlando. At Cambridge reads two papers on which A Room of One's Own is based.
1929 October: Publication of A Room of One's Own.
1930 February: Meets Ethel Smyth.
1931 October: Publication of The Waves.
1932 January: Death of Lytton Strachey. July: Letter to a Young Poet is published.
1933 Flush is published by Hogarth Press.
1934 September: Death of Roger Fry.
1937 March: Publication of The Years. July: Julian Bell dies in Spanish Civil War.
1938 June: Publication of Three Guineas.
1939 August: Virginia and Leonard move to 37 Mecklenburgh Square.
1940 July: Publication of Roger Fry: A Biography.
1941 26 February: Between the Acts is completed. 28 March: Commits suicide.
The Virginia Woolf Papers consist of 2.25 linear feet of material, dating from 1902 to 1956. Types of materials include correspondence, reading notes, drafts of essays and short stories, corrected page proofs of novels and collected essays, printed ephemera, and photographs. The bulk of the collection was assembled by Frances Hooper (1892-1986) and bequeathed to Smith College in 1986. A few additional manuscripts have been added through purchase and gift. The papers are arranged in six series.
This collection is organized into six series:
I. Correspondence of Virginia Woolf and Lytton Strachey, 1906-1956
II. Letters by Virginia Woolf, 1916-1939
III. Manuscripts by Virginia Woolf, 1916-1941
IV. Hogarth Press Ephemera, 1917-1939
V. Manuscripts by Others, 1904-1926
VI. Photographs, 1902-1927
The Virginia Woolf Papers are the physical property of the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College. Literary rights, including copyright belong to the authors of works or their legal representatives.
The bulk of the collection was assembled by Frances Hooper (1892-1986) and bequeathed to Smith College in 1986. A few additional manuscripts have been added through purchase and gift.
Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941.; Bell, Quentin.; Davidson, Angus.; Mansfield, Katherine, 1888-1923.; Strachey, Lytton, 1880-1932.; Walpole, Hugh, Sir, 1884-1941.; Sackville-West, V. (Victoria), 1892-1962.; Woolf, Leonard, 1880-1969.; Hogarth Press.; Bloomsbury group.; Novelists, English--20th century--Biography--Sources.; Women novelists, English--20th century--Biography--Sources.; Strachey, Lytton, 1880-1932.; Woolf, Leonard, 1880-1969.; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941 Common reader.; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941 Orlando.; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941 To the lighthouse.
- Series I. Correspondence of Virginia Woolf and Lytton Strachey, 0.5 linear feet
  This series includes 101 letters from Woolf, with an additional postcard addressed to Duncan Grant, and 39 letters from Strachey. Enclosures include a poem by Strachey (Box 1, folder 61) and a letter from Richard Aldington to Woolf (Box 2, folder 123). A few letters are also written by Leonard Woolf (Box 1, folders 45, 77, 78). The correspondence is accompanied by an autograph manuscript preface by James Strachey for the 1956 Hogarth Press edition of Letters: Virginia Woolf & Lytton Strachey (Box 1, folder 2). Of the 32 letters from Woolf not published in this edition, most are invitations written on halfpenny and penny postcards. One is illustrated with an anti-war graphic (Box 2, folder 137). Picture postcards in the collection depict Alfoxton House, Holford (Box 1, folder 46) and other landscapes in England and Europe. A portrait of George Eliot, with a caption by Virginia Woolf, illustrates a 14 May 1931 card to Strachey (Box 2, folder 143).
  The correspondence begins in 1906 after Virginia's elder brother, Thoby Stephen, died of typhoid fever. The correspondence ends in 1931 when Strachey died from stomach cancer. In addition to family and friends, Woolf and Strachey discuss literature and their travels. They mention Ralph Partridge, Dora Carrington, Lady Ottoline Morrell, Henry James, Katherine Mansfield, Duncan Grant, and Vanessa and Clive Bell.
- Series II. Letters by Virginia Woolf, 0.5 linear feet
  This series includes 36 letters written by Virginia Woolf about her novels and essays to editors, publishers, booksellers, private readers, and famous writers, such as Enid Bagnold, Katherine Mansfield, and Hugh Walpole. Woolf also writes to her nephew, Quentin Bell, and to a few friends, such as Vita Sackville-West, about illness, furniture, clothes, and the dangers of traveling by automobile and airplane. A series of letters to Angus Davidson, an employee of the Hogarth Press, describe Woolf's travels in Cornwall, Greece, and Italy via Holland and Germany. There are also ten letters to Robert and Mela Spira, who were Austrian refugees during World War II (Box 2, folder 164). Woolf wrote an affidavit for Robert Spira who was interned on the Isle of Man. A 1931 letter to the book dealer, Mr. Wilson, asks for a complete set of Macaulay's works. Woolf also writes to a bibliographer of Leslie Stephen about her father's work (Box 2, folder 167).
- Series III. Manuscripts by Virginia Woolf
  Boxes 3-5 hold series III., Manuscripts by Virginia Woolf, which is arranged alphabetically by title.
- Series IV. Hogarth Press Ephemera, 0.25 linear feet (15 items)
  Box 5 holds series IV., Hogarth Press Ephemera, which is arranged chronologically by item number from A Checklist of the Hogarth Press by J. Howard Woolmer
- Series V. Manuscripts by Others, 1904-1926, 0.25 linear ft.
  This series includes a letter from Anne Thackeray Ritchie to Mr. Darwin (probably one of the sons of Charles Darwin). Ritchie's letter discusses the declining health of Leslie Stephen, who died in 1904. In addition, the series contains a holograph draft by Arnold Bennett, "Books and Persons," which is a review of The Common Reader, Mrs. Dalloway, and Jacob's Room. The review appeared in the Evening Standard on 2 December 1926 under the title "Another Criticism of the New School." The other manuscripts in this series are letters written by Richard Aldington, James Strachey, Lytton Strachey, and Leonard Woolf which are housed in Series I.
- Series VI. Photographs, 1902-1927
  The only original work in this series is the 1923 framed photograph of Virginia Woolf at Garsington (box 7, folder 204). The other two photographs are modern reprints.
- Series I. Correspondence of Virginia Woolf and Lytton Strachey
  - Notes about the correspondence: holograph by James Strachey, 1952, 1 leaf (1 page) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Preface to Virginia Woolf & Lytton Strachey Letters: holograph by James Strachey, [1956], 3 leaves (3 pages) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1906 Nov 22], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Apr 22], ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1908 Apr 23, ALS, 2 leaves (7 pages). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Apr 28], ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 May 18], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Jul 28], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1908 Aug 24, ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Aug 30], ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1908 Sep 27, ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Oct 4], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Oct 14], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Nov 11], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1908 Nov 17, ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908] Nov 20, ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Nov 23], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Dec 1], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Dec 7], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Dec 19], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1908 Dec 25], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1909 Jan 3, ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909 Jan 4], ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909 Jan 26], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1909 Jan 27, ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909 Jan 28], ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1909 Jan 31, ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909] Feb 1, ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909 Feb 9], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909 Feb 16], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1909 Feb 17, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Strachey to James Strachey, 1909 Mar 9, Typescript extract of letter, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909] Jun 4, ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909 Jun 25], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1909 Oct 6], ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1909 Oct 13, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Strachey to Woolf, [1909] Nov 26, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1910 Jan 21], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1910 Nov], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1911 Nov 6], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1911 Nov 20], ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1912 Feb 13], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1912 Feb 16], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1912] May 21, ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1912 Jun 6, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). With signature of Leonard Woolf (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1912 Aug 16], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1912 Sep 1, ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1912 Nov 8, ALS, 1 leaf (2 page). (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1912] Nov 16, ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1912 Dec 1, ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1912] Dec 26, ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1914 Jan 17], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1914] Jan 29, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1914] Feb 7, AL, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1914 Dec 8], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1915 Jan], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1915 Feb 28, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1915] Oct 22, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1916 Feb 25, ALS, 2 leaves (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1916] Feb 28, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1916 Apr 15, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 61)
    With poem enclosure, typewritten, 3 leaves (3 pages)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1916 Jul 17, ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1916] Jul 25, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1916 Jul 28, ALS, 1 leaf (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 64)
    With autograph transcription by James Strachey, 1948 Feb 24, 1 leaf (1 page)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1917 Feb 21, ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1917 May 12], Hogarth Press prospectus, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1917 Jul 5], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1917 Aug 13, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1917] Aug 14, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1917 Dec 6], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1917 Dec 21, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 71)
    With autograph transcription by James Strachey, 1948 Feb 24, 2 leaves (2 pages)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1917 Dec 28], ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages) with envelope. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1918] Mar 15, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1918 Mar 19, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1918 Mar 24], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1918] Apr 23, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1918 May 24, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 77)
    Begins with TLS from Leonard Woolf
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1918 Jun 11], Telegram, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 78)
    Also from Leonard Woolf
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1918] Oct 12, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1919 Jan 29, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1919 Jan 30], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1919 May 26], ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages). (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1919 May 27, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1919 Sep] 14, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1919 Sep 28, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1919] Oct 28, ALS, 2 leaves (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Woolf to Duncan Grant, [1919 Nov 7], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1919 Nov 26], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1919 Nov 27, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1919 Nov 30], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1920] Feb 21, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1920 Apr 3, ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1920 Jul 30], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1921 Jan 24, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1921] Jan 25, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1921] Mar [30], ALS, 2 leaves (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 96)
    With picture postcard
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1921] Apr 17, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). With envelope (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1921 Aug 23, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1921 Aug 29, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1922 Feb 1], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1922 Feb 6, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1922 Feb 10, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1922] Feb [11], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1922 Feb 23], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1922 Aug 22, AL, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1922 Aug 24, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1922 Sep 19, ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages). (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1922 Oct 9, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1922 Oct 9 [?10], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1923 Jun 1], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1923 Jul 20, ALS, 1 leaf ( 1 page). (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1923 Jul ?21], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1923 Oct 4], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1923 Oct 6, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1924 Mar 21, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1924 May 1, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1924 May 2], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1924 Nov 11, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). With Hogarth Press invoice. (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1925 Jan 31], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1925] Sep 8, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1925 Sep 11, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1925 Nov 25], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1926] Jan 26, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). With TLS, Richard Aldington to Woolf, 1926 Jan 23, 1 leaf (1 page) (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1926 May], AL, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1926 Nov 17], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [?1927], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1927 Mar 21], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1927 Mar 28], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1927 Apr 12, ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Woolf to Strachey, 1927 Sep 3, ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages). (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1927 Sep 16, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1927 Nov 23], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1928 Nov 7], ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Strachey to Woolf, 1928 Dec 21, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1928] Dec 25, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1930 Jan 21], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1930 Mar 25], ACS, l leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1930 May 28], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1930 May 30], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1930 Jul 1], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1930 Nov 17], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1930 Dec 7], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1931 May 14], ACS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Woolf to Strachey, [1931] Dec 10, ALS, 1 leaf (3 pages). (Box 2, Folder 144)
- Series II. Letters by Virginia Woolf
  - Woolf to Leigh Ashton, 1930 May 27, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Woolf to Leigh Ashton, [1930 May 29], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Woolf to Enid Bagnold, 1928 Oct 28, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Woolf to Miss Batchelder, 1934 Nov 3, TLS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Woolf to Quentin Bell, 1929 Feb 17, ALS, 4 leaves (8 pages). (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Woolf to Charles E. Brumwell, 1938 Jul 12, TLS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Woolf to Catherine Carswell, [1933] Aug 3, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Woolf to Angus Davidson, [1926] Dec 25, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Woolf to Angus Davidson, [1927 Apr], ALS, 2 leaves (3 pages). (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Woolf to Angus Davidson, 1927 Apr 14, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Woolf to Angus Davidson, [1927] Dec 22, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - Woolf to Angus Davidson, [1935] Apr 11, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Woolf to Angus Davidson, 1938 May 26, ALS, 1 leaf (1 pages). (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - Woolf to Crosby Gaige, 1928 Oct 29, TLS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 158)
  - Woolf to Duncan Grant
    See: box 1, folder 87
  - Woolf to William Jackson, 1930 Apr 29, TLS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 159)
  - Woolf to Katherine Mansfield, [1921] Feb 13, ALS, 2 leaves (4 pages). (Box 2, Folder 160)
  - Woolf to Robert Nichols, 1936 Sep 24, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 161)
    Postcard with envelope. Written on one of Leonard Woolf's printed postcards.
  - Woolf to Margery Olivier, [1916] Jan 13, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 162)
  - Woolf to Margery Olivier, [1916] Jan 21, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 163)
  - Woolf to Vita Sackville-West, [1939 Feb 26], ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 163a)
    Purchased.
  - Woolf to Mela and Robert Spira, 1939 Jan 11-1940 Oct 2, ALS & TLS & Postcard 11 letters ,11 leaves, (15 pages). (Box 2, Folder 164)
    (with 8 envelopes, bound)
  - Woolf to J. C. Squire, [1919] Nov 18, ALS, 1 leaf (2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 165)
  - Woolf to Hugh Walpole, 1932 Mar 3, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 166)
  - Woolf to Carlton F. Wells, 1936 Nov 19, TLS, with envelope 1 leaf ( 2 pages). (Box 2, Folder 167)
  - Woolf to Mr. Wilson, 1931 Dec 8, TLS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 168)
  - Woolf to Unidentified, 1928 Oct 17, TLS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 2, Folder 169)
- Series III. Manuscripts by Virginia Woolf
  - "As to Criticism": holograph, [1924?] Feb 4, 6 leaves (6 pages). (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - The Common Reader. Donald C. Brace to Crosby Gaige, 1925 Jul 14, ALS, 1 leaf (1 page). (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - The Common Reader., Orange quarter leather case for page proofs. (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - The Common Reader: page proofs, corrected, 1925., 157 leaves (314 pages). (Box 3, Folder 173-74)
    Stamped: FIRST PROOF, R. & R. Clark, LTD., EDIINBURGH, 13-19 MAR. 1925. Corrected by Virginia Woolf for the American edition (published 14 May 1925, by Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc.) Includes tear sheets of "Miss Ormerod" from The Dial, December 1924 77:6, 466-74. Printer's annotations throughout.
  - Italian: autograph manuscript notebook, 1916 Jun 7., 70 leaves (87 pages). (Box 3, Folder 175)